-[distorted noises]
-[tense music playing]
[Bethany] I thought I heard
something fall. and then. um. Murphy bark.
Dylan. she said
she thinks she saw someone.
[Dylan] And I saw this guy in all black
and. like. this mask.
I didn't know what to do.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
I jumped up and locked my door
because I was so scared. [shudders]
[voice wavering] After that.
I didn't hear anything.
[tense music swelling]
[officer] Moscow Police Department.
If you're in here. announce yourself.
Moscow Police Department.
Breaking news about a murder mystery.
Four college students were killed
early Sunday morning.
their bodies found in an off-campus house
near the University of Idaho.
What happened?
What could've happened?
This was something that someone
thought about doing. planned on doing.
[detective] Have any of your roommates
complained about anyone stalking them?
[Bethany] She could see
a man's silhouette staring at her.
[engine starts]
[Kristi] This person
snuck into their house
after circling it like a shark!
[Lilly] The three girls
were beautiful and popular.
Was this a crime against women?
[Bethany] She said. "Someone's here."
and she screamed and ran downstairs.
[woman] The killer is still loose. How do
I know he's not gonna target someone else?
[Darline] I call him Demon.
That's my name for him.
Demon.
[tense music builds to a climax]
[music fades]
["Moscow Drinking Team"
by Colby Acuff playing]
♪ Here's to the vandals in the crowd ♪
♪ All just out there. livin' the dream ♪
♪ Part of the one and only
Moscow drinking team ♪
Moscow. Idaho. Under the blankets.
University of Idaho was always
kind of on my radar for college.
First time I visited.
I kind of got this sense
of just family and closeness.
and I think that's where I stem from.
I knew I wanted to go there
the first time I visited.
♪ At this point. it's about 10:45 ♪
♪ And I'm at the bar
Gettin' breathalyzed ♪
[Maya] University of Idaho was probably
some of the best years of my life.
I think college is
a very special little bubble
of this time
where you have a lot of freedom.
Xana and I sure had a lot of fun.
Hi. my name is Xana Kernodle.
I'm a Marketing major
here at the University of Idaho.
[Maya] Xana was a junior
when she moved into King Street
with Maddie. Kaylee. Dylan. and Bethany.
["Remember (Acoustic)"
by Becky Hill playing]
[Maya] They were all Pi Phis.
and Kaylee was in a different sorority.
Hi. everyone. My name is Kaylee Goncalves.
and I'm a General Studies major.
[Baylie] Maddie and Kaylee.
you know. grew up best friends.
Their relationship was so fun to watch
because they were like sisters.
They fought like sisters.
they did everything like sisters.
I love you! [giggling]
["Moscow Drinking Team" continues]
♪ But I'm almost certain I can guarantee ♪
[Maya] If you're in Greek life.
everyone knows everyone.
and so we would do mixers
with fraternities and sororities
or date dashes.
One day. Ethan kind of appeared
and it was an instant
kind of connection you could see.
Xana and Ethan were the life of the party.
so them together just made a lot of sense.
-[woman] Aw. that's kinda cute.
-[groans]
[Maya] They're so cute it's gross.
You know. I'm tired of seeing you guys
just be so adorable.
My name is Ethan Chapin.
I'm from Mount Vernon. Washington.
[Peter] I was in the Sigma Chi fraternity
with Ethan and his brother. Hunter.
Ethan was like a big teddy bear.
You could never be upset around him.
He had this love for country music
and that's my thing.
I loved country music.
He knew the songs.
so I was like. "Hell. this guy's cool."
"I want to hang out with him."
♪ You're doing fine ♪
♪ 'Cause love's a smoke ring ♪
[Peter] That was the best time in my life.
-Three!
-♪ Here's to the vandals in the crowd ♪
[screaming]
[Peter] Man. I just wish we could go back
in a heartbeat because it's so much fun.
♪ Part of the one and only
Moscow drinking team ♪
["Moscow Drinking Team" ends]
Cut.
[moody ethereal music playing]
[Baylie] In your 20s.
the world is really at your fingertips.
brimming with endless possibilities
and every dream is kind of in reach.
And you're just so excited
for what's to come next.
and you feel a little bit like an adult.
I was never worried
about anything. um. happening.
And it's just the time of your life.
And looking back. I wish
that I could go back to those times.
before. you know.
before this had all happened.
[operator] 911.
location of your emergency?
[Bethany. in anguished voice]
Something's happened in our house
and we don't know what.
[operator] What is the address
of the emergency?
[Bethany] 1122 King Road.
[woman] I'll talk to you guys. We're. um…
We live at the Whites.
so we're next to them.
[operator] And tell me
exactly what's going on.
[woman] Um… One of our…
one of the roommates has passed out.
and she was drunk last night
and she's not waking up.
-[Bethany] This--
-[operator] Are you with the patient?
I need someone to keep the phone.
Stop passing it around.
Is she breathing?
[Bethany] She's knocked out! What's wrong?
She's not waking up.
[Hunter J.] Xana!
[operator] Okay. one moment.
I'm getting help started that way.
[tense music playing]
Dispatching Moscow law.
ambulance for unconsciousness.
1122 King Road.
Units responding.
RPs advising the patient
is not conscious. not breathing.
[officer 1] I'm in service en route
to King Road. I'm out at King Road.
[operator] Copy.
[officer 1] Where's she at?
-[woman 1] Here. [indistinct chatter]
-[officer 1] Yep. Where's she at?
-[woman 2] She's at the close one.
-[woman 1] Yes. She's right there.
[indistinct chatter]
-[officer 1] Where at? Up here?
-[Hunter J.] We got a call… Up here.
We got a call from one of the roommates
that there was someone here…
[indistinct dialogue]
And I came and checked in here…
And I didn't check there yet. but…
[officer 1] Okay. Stay back there. please.
Fuck!
[moody dramatic music playing]
Thirteen. I think we have a homicide.
Two college-aged people appearing
both to be deceased. Lots of blood.
[officer 2] I copy.
[operator] Units responding.
per the radio traffic between officers.
there appears to be two college-age people
appearing both deceased. lots of blood.
[loud clatter]
[officer 1] Slow down.
There's a… Just come here. It's…
There's two…
Looks like fatalities.
[music becomes tense]
[officer 2. clears throat] Okay.
Nobody's allowed to leave. for now. okay?
Um… Just stay here for me. please.
[distant siren blaring]
Okay. Here.
Can you guys go over
to the dumpster for me. please?
[officer 1] Find them?
[Hunter J.] Yeah. the roommates
called me this morning
to come check because they thought
they saw someone in here last night
and they went into their rooms.
I came over when they called.
and I opened the door and I saw that.
[officer 1] Okay. Let's go and step
downstairs. Anybody else upstairs?
-[Hunter J.] I don't know.
-[officer 1] Don't touch anything.
[Hunter J.] I grabbed that knife
because when I went in.
I didn't know
if there was someone in there. but…
[officer 1] Okay.
-I grabbed it to make sure--
-[officer 1] Got your ID with you?
-[Hunter J.] No. I can tell you my name.
-[officer 1] Okay. Just stand right here.
Why don't you go
and have a seat over here? Outside.
One second. please. Okay. you have
to step outside. Let's go outside.
House isn't clear yet.
Moscow Police Department.
If you're in here. announce yourself.
[officer 2] Fuck.
-[officer 1] Police Department.
-[officer 2] On the third floor. going up.
Hey. puppy.
[sighs]
Oh. man…
-Fuck. dude.
-[officer 1] Yeah.
[officer 3] Forty-Six. Thirteen.
Let me know when 1-0-2 arrives.
[officer 1] Thirteen. we have two
additional deceased on the third floor.
[officer 2] I copy.
[moody music playing]
-[officer 1] Careful. it's. uh…
-[officer 2] Yeah. we're gonna need…
everybody. I think. We got four deceased.
Would you be open
to taking a dog to the impound for me?
Oh. boy.
Justin Olson's gonna come pick this dog up
and take him to the pound for us.
Come on.
Do you mind holding on to him a second?
[indistinct chatter]
[officer 4] Moscow 120. Same traffic.
[operator] I copy. and just
to keep you updated. per radio traffic.
it sounds like they found
two additional deceased in the house.
[Anthony] That day. I was at home.
It was my day off.
I got the phone call.
I was not the on-call commander.
so I knew that phone call
was probably not a good thing.
I definitely did not expect to hear
that we had not only a homicide.
but a quadruple homicide.
Without going into too much detail.
it was absolutely horrific.
It was immediately apparent that all four
had succumbed to stab wounds
as a likely cause of death.
That's something
that nobody expects to ever see
and something you can never unsee
once you see it.
I know not only myself.
but every officer
that was involved that day.
has had a hard time with that.
[officer 1] I walked all the way around
and didn't see any blood anywhere.
or anything like that.
[Anthony] Our detective sergeant.
when he arrived on scene.
he recognized that this was a major event.
He immediately called
our partners at the Idaho State Police
and asked them to come up and assist.
[officer 1] I'm guessing you're…
[Anthony] This was so outside anything
that we had dealt with
at the Police Department.
[officer 1] Here. I came around back
when we first got here
and there's a back door that was open
with one track of footprints in the snow.
[Anthony] The officers.
when they first went through the scene.
the back door was ajar.
it was slightly open.
And we knew that none of our officers
had come and gone from that door.
[officer 5] So I got
about a size 13-and-a-half shoe here.
coming and going.
rounds that log. goes back down that way.
[intriguing music playing]
No. uh…
No weapon we've been able to locate?
We haven't moved anybody.
but I'd ascertain it's probably not here.
-Yeah.
-[officer 2] But…
Looks like there's some dried blood
on the sink.
but there's not any around it.
[Anthony] 1122 King Road
was a three-story home.
On the third floor were two rooms.
and the room to the right
was where we found two female victims.
Going downstairs
to what would be the main floor.
just at the bottom of the stairs.
was another bedroom. and that was empty.
Off of that was the living room area.
Off of the living room area.
down a short hallway.
was another bedroom.
and that is where
we found the male and female victims.
Down at the bottom level.
so the street level. was another bedroom.
We found traces of blood
throughout the house.
We also found a knife sheath
in the third-floor bedroom
laying next to one of the victims.
We knew that was going to be
something of high importance.
[officer 2] Who'd like a blanket?
It's temporary.
Would anybody like one?
For your feet? To stand on?
-[Dylan] I'll take one.
-[officer 2] Okay.
[Anthony] As we started talking
to people involved.
we found out there were roommates
that were home. Dylan and Bethany.
They were able to advise information
of who else were roommates in the home.
-[officer 2] Who's Xana?
-[Dylan] Xana is the girl in there.
-[officer 2] Is the girl… This one?
-[Dylan] Yeah.
-[officer 2] Do you know how old she is?
-She's 20.
[officer 2] The guy that lives here.
his name is what?
-Or he's usually here. Ethan.
-[Dylan] Oh. Ethan… Chapin.
[officer 2] And. um…
So Ethan. how old is Ethan?
[Dylan] I believe he just turned 20.
And then there's Maddie Mogen
and Kaylee up top.
-[officer 2] How old is Maddie?
-[Dylan] She's 21.
[officer 2] How old is Kaylee?
[Dylan] Over 21. I believe she's 21 or 22.
-Sorry. I don't fully remember.
-[officer 2] It's okay.
-You're doing great.
-[Dylan] Thanks. I'm scared.
[officer 2] I'm asking a lot of you.
so I appreciate…
-[Dylan] Sorry if I don't say anything.
-[officer 2] You're doing very well.
[Bethany] Maddie and Kaylee
came home from the club.
[officer 2] Do you know how long
they were there? Till closing. at least?
[Bethany] Yeah.
[Dylan] I was in my room.
And I was trying to go to bed.
and I heard Kaylee go upstairs.
Like. "I'm gonna go to sleep now.
She's going upstairs."
And then. all of a sudden.
I heard her scream.
[voice wavering] And she ran downstairs
'cause she saw someone.
That's what I'm pretty sure she said.
"Someone's here."
And she screamed and just ran downstairs.
I called her name.
but I jumped up and locked my door
because I was so scared.
And then I heard her go in…
I think it was the bathroom.
And I remember her sobbing.
I remember hearing this guy's voice
that I didn't recognize saying.
"You're going to be okay. I'm gonna help."
But I don't know how to explain it.
It wasn't in a nice way.
It was a weird way. Like. a weird tone.
[officer 2] "You're gonna be okay."
-"I'm gonna help you."
-[Dylan] Yeah.
[officer 2] You didn't hear anything
from Kaylee anymore?
[Dylan] No. after that
I didn't hear anything.
[officer 2] Okay.
[Dylan] So then I kept calling her name.
On my phone.
I called Xana. Maddie. and Kaylee
and none of them answered.
So then I opened up the door to look
and that's when I saw the guy pass by.
He looked at me. but he didn't
come towards me or say anything.
Which was really confusing to me.
I don't understand that.
I'm pretty sure he went out the side door.
I didn't know what to do.
-[officer 2] Four this morning?
-[Dylan] 4:00 a.m.. yes.
[mysterious music playing]
[Anthony] Just off of the kitchen area
would have been Dylan's room.
She said she saw a male figure
in the living room. dressed in all black.
Their eyes met. They saw each other.
For whatever reason. the perpetrator
continued to walk towards the kitchen.
and Dylan shut her door and locked it
out of fear. and the perpetrator left.
She had tried
to get a hold of her other roommates
and she ended up getting Bethany.
Bethany was downstairs.
in her room on the bottom floor.
Bethany told her to come downstairs
and Dylan opened her door.
ran downstairs and spent
the rest of the night with Bethany.
Our officers were able to find out that
Bethany and Dylan called a friend
and a friend's boyfriend to come over
so they could have someone come check on
the rest of the roommates.
The boyfriend had. when he arrived.
is the one who entered the home.
went upstairs
and saw Xana and Ethan deceased.
Jesus. man.
What happened?
[officer 5] So. uh. I did call Aaron
and I heard him checking the service.
Just said. "Hey. these kids are gonna need
some sort of counselor to talk to."
-Cap's got it taken care of.
-[officer 5] Cool.
That's taken care of.
One girl was in there.
Did you hear that part of it?
-[officer 5] Mm-mm.
-There was another girl that was in here.
saw a guy walk in with a ski mask on
and. uh. locked herself in her room.
-Heard all of this shit going on.
-[officer 5] Holy shit.
And she didn't call last night?
It happened at four.
[officer 5] This girl's lucky to be alive.
She probably didn't make a peep
and locked her door.
Probably didn't know that she was there.
[Anthony] We asked the question.
why did the roommates wait eight hours
to call the police?
There are so many reasons why you may not.
People are in shock. it's traumatic.
I mean. I can't imagine being of that age
and being able to comprehend
that this horrific thing just occurred.
-[intriguing music playing]
-[chatter over police radio]
[Cooper] My apartment
was backed up into that King house.
probably ten yards from the front door
of their house.
And you could see it
right from my bedroom.
Um…
This is gonna be tough.
This is gonna be real tough. Um…
I woke up. I looked out my window
and heard a bit of what was going on.
screaming. crying and stuff.
I saw some of the girls
sitting out there with the. with the cop.
And so. my first thought was.
something's wrong with.
you know. Ethan and Xana.
My first thing was Hunter.
Ethan's brother.
We were all in Sigma Chi together.
And so. I went and got shoes.
went and grabbed Hunter
from the Sigma Chi house.
I woke him up.
I was like. "Hey. have you heard
from Ethan or Xana?"
He was panicking. I was like. "What are
you talking about? What's going on?"
Tries to call him. no answer.
Um… So we're walking over there.
and he's like. "What's going on?"
I'm like. "I don't know.
I don't have any answers for you. I just…"
And I saw Hunter Johnson.
He just told Hunter Chapin
Ethan and Xana weren't there anymore.
I mean. how do you process that. you know?
It's hard to see everyone
figure out what was going on.
For some reason. in the moment. I didn't
feel like it was my place to be there.
So I walked back up to my apartment.
And there's my girlfriend. Addie.
and my roommates and their girlfriends
and told them that they're gone.
-Um…
-[music stops]
It's pretty hard.
[melancholic music playing]
[woman] Ethan. look at me. Smile!
Say cheese.
[Cooper] Ethan. he was one
of the most kind people
you will ever run into in your life.
He'd walk into a room
and the energy would light up
and would genuinely make you smile.
[Maya] Xana and Ethan instantly were
best friends from the very beginning.
I could kinda tell
she was starting to like him
because Xana and I had
a ritual every single morning.
Because before Xana moved
into the King Street house.
we lived next door to each other.
I'd wake up and I would go into
Xana's room and say good morning.
Or she'd wake up
and come and say good morning.
just whoever woke up first.
Then I started noticing. you know.
Xana hasn't been coming to my room
so often in the mornings. That's weird.
So I would go into her room
and little did I know. there's Ethan.
And I'd be like. "Hello. Ethan.
Good morning. Good to see you."
He really loved her.
I mean. you could see it.
They were made for each other.
[officer 2] I'll be right back
with you. okay?
-[J] Hello?
-[officer 2] Hey. J. Sorry to bug ya.
Um… we have
a quadruple homicide on campus.
Can you come in and start.
uh… just man the street?
-[text alert]
-[woman 1] So they can text you…
-…so fucked up.
-[person crying]
[woman 2] You could have told us
that happened before they sent a text.
[officer 2] I have no idea
what you're talking about.
[woman 2] They sent a text
to the entire university
before even telling us what happened.
Obviously we know.
but it'd be nice to have a confirmation.
[Blaine] I got a call
from the Moscow Police Department.
He said. "Blaine. we have
four dead individuals."
"We think they may be college students."
And I was just flabbergasted.
All kinds of questions
go through your mind.
How? Who? Why? What happened?
[mysterious music playing]
The protocol for us at the institution
when we learn a crime has occurred
is to use the Vandal Alert system
so we can get information out immediately.
[officer 2] Hey. ma'am. Ma'am?
Can you stop there for me?
Can you come back down here?
We're not gonna have
anybody come back this way.
-[woman] Gonna go to my friend's house.
-[officer 2] They up here?
-[woman] Yeah.
-[officer 2] Let's walk on the road.
[Anthony] It was a chaotic scene.
There were people coming out
of all sorts of residences around.
They knew something was going on.
People were starting to get upset.
[officer 2] Hey. can you guys
stay here for a little bit?
-[man 1] Yeah.
-[officer 2] Is that okay?
You know. it's ongoing panic.
and phone calls. texts.
Everyone's starting to know
and freak out and…
[mysterious music playing]
That Vandal Alert said "homicide."
That's a pretty heavy word.
And most of us at that point knew
that they weren't alive anymore.
but still didn't know what happened.
No one had the answers.
Everyone was talking.
saying different things.
[man 2] Are you the one to ask
what's going on there?
[officer 2] Yeah. I can't tell you.
though. So. um…
Yeah. if everybody could just stay inside.
We didn't get a heads-up
that they were going to put out the alert.
We would have preferred
that that information
would have been collaborated with us
prior to it going out.
because on the scene we had four victims.
We had to not only identify the victims.
and then start working diligently
to get a hold of their next of kin
and notify them.
And when the university put out the alert.
that information started being shared
before we were able to.
[people crying]
[Maya] I had texted Xana
and was like.
"Hey. did you get the Vandal Alert?"
No response.
Checked her location. She was at home.
So I was like. "That's weird."
Immediately. the sororities
and fraternities did head counts.
so they account for everyone
who's in the house.
Whether you live in or you don't.
they make sure that
all of their people are accounted for.
That's how I kind of found out that
Xana and Maddie weren't accounted for.
[melancholic music playing]
Throughout my whole time at Moscow
there haven't been too many Vandal Alerts.
Nothing ever that bad happens here.
We all watch over each other.
have each other's backs.
Xana and I had Finance class together.
She was kind of freaking out
'cause she needed to get an A on this test
in order to get a good grade
in the class and stuff like that.
so. she was asking me if we could go
to the library tutoring sessions
on that Sunday.
And then when we got that Vandal Alert
I was texting her and calling her.
Couldn't get through to her.
So then I got in contact
with her sister. Jazzmin.
[Jazzmin] Xana's my little sister.
Growing up. it was just my dad and us.
Once I went to college.
we got really close.
and then she went to college like.
you know. ten minutes away from me.
[Jeff] Jazzmin was
seven miles away at WSU.
so they could see each other.
Knowing that they were close to each other
was a little more comforting.
[contemplative music playing]
[Jazzmin] The weekend
of November 12th and 13th.
we had the Wazzu football game on Saturday
that my dad and I went to
with a bunch of our friends.
He wanted Xana and Ethan to come too.
but they really wanted to go
to the University of Idaho football game.
I was pushing for it. them to come over.
but they didn't make it
over there that night.
The next day. my dad left.
and he was gonna go check on Xana
because she needed
a light fixed in her car.
[Jeff] I was gonna stop by Xana's.
I called and she didn't answer. and I go.
"You know what?
She's probably sleeping in."
It was a cloudy day.
Really bad day was what it was.
[tense music playing]
So I just started driving out of town.
and I got about ten miles out.
and Jazzmin had got a call
from a couple of Xana's friends.
"Hey Jazz. I'm not exactly sure
if you've heard what's going on.
but there's something
that happened on King Street."
Started calling Xana and Ethan.
and I started calling
some of Xana's best friends and…
I called my dad and I told him
that he should probably turn around
because something bad happened.
[Jeff] I just stopped the car.
So I raced back down there. and…
[chatter over police radio]
They had the crime tape
100. 200 feet off the house
so it rounded the whole thing.
They wouldn't let nobody
within that distance of it.
[Jazzmin] There's no ambulances.
there's nothing.
so. I didn't know what to believe.
I just asked if I could go see my sister.
They just didn't say anything.
and I didn't know what was going on.
I was approached by a male. and he said.
"My daughter lives in that house."
They told me that we needed to go
to the police station. They wanted to…
to talk to us.
[melancholic music playing]
[Anthony] I've done. unfortunately.
many death notifications in my career…
but that's definitely got to be
one of the hardest I've ever had to do.
[Jazzmin] We were just confused.
We were shocked.
We didn't know what happened at all.
But I had all this adrenaline.
and I think my dad the same.
We just. we didn't know.
What do you do in that situation?
Like. no one knows.
So that was really. really hard.
I just left after that. They told me.
"There's nothing you can do.
You can't see anything or d…"
There's nothing I could do.
It was the best thing I could do.
I couldn't deal with it.
You know?
[Kristi] November 13th.
You know. it was a normal day.
I got a phone call from my niece. Sabrina.
She was hysterical.
She told me that she thought
something bad had happened to Kaylee.
[melancholic music continues]
[voice wavering] And she said.
"Aunt Kristi. I think Kaylee's dead."
Her husband's cousin lives down there.
and he said there was a party.
and somebody went in
and shot up the party.
and Kaylee got shot.
I tried Kaylee first.
Her phone went straight to voicemail.
And then I called her sister. Alivea.
[tense music playing]
[Alivea] I had two or three missed calls
from my mom and a missed call from my dad.
That's always kind of a red alert.
you know. something's happening.
So I call her back.
I could hear the panic in her voice.
I say. "Okay. I'll start calling around.
I'll talk to you in a few."
I reach out to some of the roommates
that Kaylee had in the house.
And I reached out on Instagram.
Basically just said. "Hey.
heard that maybe an accident happened."
"Can you just have Kaylee
get a hold of us?"
And. of course. in between this.
I'm calling Kaylee. I'm calling Maddie.
I'm not getting through.
but it's not really alarming to me yet.
[Kristi] I started calling Maddie.
Her phone would just ring and ring.
I'm still not understanding
why Maddie's not answering.
I called Maddie's mom. Karen.
and I said. "Have you heard
about something is going on?"
She said. "We're on it.
Scott and I are driving down."
"We're 25 minutes away from Moscow."
"We're going to pick up the girls.
They're fine."
"We're picking up the girls."
I knew in my heart
that they weren't fine.
And I was like. "Okay. Karen. Okay."
[melancholic music playing]
[Steve] When your child has a relationship
with somebody else
and gets to that point
of a true best friend.
your families kind of blend together. and…
-[Kaylee] Say hi. Maddie.
-Hi.
[Steve] She had that with Maddie.
It's just me and Maddie
out here by the pool.
Soaking up the sunshine.
[Kristi] I started getting messages
in my Facebook saying.
"I'm so sorry for your loss."
And I'm like.
"No. no. no. no! This can't be real.
you know?" And. uh…
And that sheriff pulled up.
I'd actually took off
running to the bedroom because I knew.
[Steve] The officer just tells us that
not only our daughter has passed away.
but Maddie has passed away as well.
And I'd just gotten off the phone
with Karen. Maddie's mother. and Scotty.
and we knew that they were
probably ten. 15 minutes away
from showing up on site.
They're in Moscow.
and from what I've been told.
they were told at the police department.
[Anthony] Every human being
reacts differently.
or uniquely. to grief.
I've given death notifications where
I've had individuals almost strike me.
I've had others
that they were inconsolable.
And none of the reactions are…
There's no wrong reaction.
I'm a father as well.
And I could not imagine
what they. not only went through.
but continue to go through
with the loss of their children.
[music fades]
[officer 6] We're gonna do
a neighborhood canvass.
So. I need to know
who's available here to start with me.
-[indistinct chatter]
-[officer 7] I can.
[moody dramatic music playing]
[Anthony] Information in any investigation
is important to keep close to the vest.
[knocking]
As much as we would like to share
information in investigations
so that people were informed.
it puts everyone at risk.
[officer 2] Did you guys hear anything.
see anything last night or this morning?
[woman] Can you tell us what happened?
[officer 2] We can't tell you
what's going on right now.
Also. we can't have the offender.
the perpetrator.
knowing what information we have.
They could use that
to further disappear or do it again.
-[officer 2] Hello. Huh?
-[man 1] What's going on? What's going on?
-[officer 2] I can't tell you.
-[man 1] Really?
[officer 3] Yeah. Sorry.
In order to keep the case pure
and whole and untainted.
we need to preserve
the integrity of the case.
[man 2] Yeah. I didn't hear anything
last night. I was home all night.
Nothing out of the ordinary for me.
With this case. we relied on our partners
with the Idaho State Police
and their forensics folks.
They were in that house
looking for everything.
And it took hours and hours.
As far as evidence we collected.
the knife sheath
was obviously a big portion.
We wanted to make sure that
that got forensically analyzed
as quickly as possible.
[moody dramatic music fades]
[Jack] Can I… Can I ask
what's going on? [indistinct]
[officer 2] Where are you living at?
[Jack] I live right over there.
but that's my ex-girlfriend of five years.
[officer 2] Trying to figure out
what's going on? Okay.
I'll have you sit here for a second.
We'll have someone talk with you. okay?
Do you wanna sit in the car for a second?
Just so we can keep you separated
from the people that were. uh. around.
[Jack] Trying to find out what's going on.
[officer 2] I'll have someone
talk to you. okay?
I appreciate it. Thanks.
Guy just walked up to me and said.
"Can I talk to you? What's going on?"
He said… I said. "Oh. Who are you?
Do you live here or something?"
He says. "No. that's my ex-girlfriend
of five years that's in there."
"I don't know what's going on.
I live right over here."
[tense music playing]
[Baylie] Jack is my cousin.
Jack started dating Kaylee
sophomore year of high school.
They went to the same high school.
and ended up going to the same college.
She was graduating soon.
and she had just landed a pretty big job
in Austin. Texas. actually.
I was surprised.
She's been here her whole life.
But I knew. I mean.
she was very spontaneous.
And I was like. "Oh. that makes sense."
I think Kaylee
and Jack were on a break at this time.
She kinda just was like.
"I'm just. you know. going with life
and try to adventure
by myself for a little."
On that day.
I was at my mom's store in Hayden. Idaho.
and I got a call from my good friend
at University of Idaho.
She said. "I think Kaylee passed away."
And I think
I kinda went into a state of denial.
I was kind of like.
"What do you mean? Um. like Kaylee who?"
And I just. I couldn't get myself to
grasp the fact that it could be my Kaylee.
I was trying to call Jack's sister.
She was bawling when I answered the phone.
She said that Jack was
in the back of a cop car.
[Jack] I wanted to speak to someone
about what's going on.
[officer 2] Give me just a second.
I understand your dog's upstairs?
[Jack] I'm not worried about my dog.
I'm worried about what happened.
I don't know anything.
Got a guy here
that's the ex of one of them.
-He's detained in this car at the moment.
-[officer 5] Yeah.
[officer 2] Okay.
[Anthony] It's typical
in a case of this nature
for the ex-boyfriend
to be a person of interest.
and so it was very important
for us to talk with him.
-[Jack] I just wanna know what's going on.
-[officer 2] Get with you in a minute.
[Anthony] Someone who kills somebody
with a knife. it's very personal.
There were theories about
was it some relationship gone bad?
Was it a fellow student?
We didn't know if it was
somebody that they knew or not.
so many people were brought back
to the Police Department.
and our detectives were going one by one.
having interviews with each one of them.
That included Jack DuCoeur.
who we learned
was the ex-boyfriend of Kaylee.
[tense music continues]
At this point. I felt so helpless.
I'm over a thousand miles away.
What can I do?
And then I get a text
from my sister Autumn.
and she said. "The cops are here."
"She's dead. Alivea."
And I just said. "Okay. I'm on my way."
I basically just needed to get there
as fast as possible.
My husband's driving.
My kids are sleeping in the back here.
At this point. I'm not crying. I'm okay.
And then that's when
I start thinking to myself.
if something happened last night.
they're gonna call someone.
Kaylee's phone
was on my parents' little plan.
I asked my mom to give me the password
so that I could log into it.
I got into the account.
Kaylee had not called 911 at any point.
but I did notice that she had called Jack
quite a few times.
The calls first started
some time around 2:00 a.m.
They eventually ended
some time around 3:00 a.m.
I'm thinking it wasn't out of the ordinary
for Kaylee to do that.
But. of course.
that's something that looks odd
when you know what has happened.
[detective] We're trying to collect
as much information as we can
to get a picture on what's going on
and figure out
where to start looking. okay?
-[Jack] Okay.
-[detective] Um…
Do you have any idea
who would do something like this?
[Jack] Um… I…
[tense music ends]
[moody electronic music playing]
[moody electronic music fades]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm